(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI LIVE TOUR 2024
SPECTRA of NOVA
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention / ご来場のお客様へ
Attention / To our guests
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
受注生産グッズ
Made-to-order goods
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To all attendees
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Vocal cheering is permitted.
受注生産グッズ ①
Made-to-Order Goods 1
受注生産グッズ ②
Made-to-Order Goods 2
受注生産グッズ ③
Made-to-Order Goods 3
受注生産グッズ ④
Made-to-Order Goods 4
受注生産グッズ ⑤
Made-to-Order Goods 5
SPONSORS
最近行ったのよ、カラオケ。
I went to karaoke recently.
なんかさ、2時間で解散と思うじゃん。
Like, you think it's over after two hours.
でもそっからなのよ。
But that's when it really starts.
え？
What?
いろんなことできるわけ。やばいぞ。
You can do all sorts of things. It's crazy.
うまい！
Nice!
PLAY! NEW (X). X PARK
X PARK最高！
X PARK is the best!
JOYSOUND X1
ふくや
Fukuya
明太子が...！
The mentaiko is...!
キレオ？
Kireo?
キメ！
Pose!
明太子が生まれ変わる
I've come up with a new technique
新しい技を編み出しました。行きます！
to transform mentaiko. Here I go!
ふくやの明太子から生まれたメンチーズシリーズ！
The Men Cheese series, born from Fukuya's mentaiko!
ピリリな味わい。
A spicy flavor.
マコも大好き！
Mako loves it too!
詳しくはWebで！
Check the website for details!
My name is Clarity Powers and I think the song
"Spectra" by Suisei-chan is quite a song for us girls.
And this song is much better than anything else I could play.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention
受注生産グッズ ①
Made-to-order Merchandise ①
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI LIVE TOUR 2024 "Spectra of Nova"
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention / ご来場のお客様へ
Attention / To our audience members
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
受注生産グッズ ①
Order-made Goods ①
受注生産グッズ ②
Order-made Goods ②
受注生産グッズ ③
Order-made Goods ③
受注生産グッズ ④
Order-made Goods ④
受注生産グッズ ⑤
Order-made Goods ⑤
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI LIVE TOUR 2024 "Spectra of Nova"
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI LIVE TOUR 2024 "SPECTRA of NOVA"
ファンメッセージ 寄せ書き
Fan Messages Montage
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK
受注生産グッズ 受付中
Made-to-order goods now available
ファンメッセージ 寄せ書き
Fan Messages Montage
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI LIVE TOUR 2024
SPECTRA OF NOVA
すいちゃん！可愛い！
Sui-chan! You're cute!
すいちゃん！最高！
Sui-chan! You're the best!
本日は、星街すいせいライブツアー2024
Today, for the Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024
『Spectra of Nova』にご来場いただき、誠にありがとうございます。
"Spectra of Nova", thank you very much for coming.
星街すいせいです！
It's Hoshimachi Suisei!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
I'd like to give you some guidance so that you can enjoy the live show until the end.
公演中の撮影、録音、
Photography, recording,
録画機材の使用は、固くお断りいたします。
and the use of recording equipment during the performance are strictly prohibited.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、
In the unlikely event that you feel unwell,
無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
please don't push yourself and let a nearby staff member know.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込む、
Acts such as moshing, diving, throwing things onto the stage,
たこ焼きを食べるなどなど、他の皆様の迷惑になったり、
eating takoyaki, and so on, that disturb others
公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
or interfere with the performance are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
いいお返事！
Good answer!
また、本公演は映像配信および、
Also, for this performance, cameras for video streaming
写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
and photography are in the venue, and the audience seats may be filmed.
喜んでます。
They're happy.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がございますので、
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used for promotions, etc.
あらかじめご了承ください。
Thank you for your understanding in advance.
いいお返事！
Good answer!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは『#駆け巡る星街』。
Also, the hashtag for the live show is "#Kake-meguru Hoshimachi".
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくださいね！
Please use the hashtag and build up the excitement!
アナウンスは以上です。
That's all for the announcements.
大阪の皆さん！
Everyone in Osaka!
ライブが始まる前からもう、声枯らそうとしてるんじゃないですか？！
Aren't you trying to lose your voice even before the live starts?!
まだまだ、いけますよね？！
You can still go, right?!
開演までもう少しです。
It's just a little longer until the start.
みんなで一緒に盛り上がりましょう！ありがとうございました！
Let's get excited together! Thank you very much!
Are you ready?
大阪ー！
Osaka!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get fired up!
損得も出前も
Both profit and delivery
駆け引き上手な大人
Adults who are good at bargaining
ダメなの
It's no good
そんな言葉使用できない
I can't use those words
できない
I can't
鉛筆で描いてきて
Draw it with a pencil
進化し続けるテクノロジー
Ever-evolving technology
伝えて
Convey
人肌の温もりね
The warmth of human skin
このままずっと降り止まない
It won't stop falling just like this
雨の世界だ
It's a world of rain
もう悲しくない
I'm not sad anymore
人は慣れる生き物だから
Because humans are creatures that adapt
走馬灯になった青春の
Of my youth that's turned into a kaleidoscope
何ページ目だったっけ
Which page was it on?
今君に会いたいと
Thinking I want to see you now
涙込み上げる
Tears well up inside
踏んだり蹴ったり
When it rains, it pours
十一寸前 人生の天気だ
Just a step away, it's the weather of life
嵐地帯
A storm zone
踊りこなしていくんだ 透明で 鮮明で
Dancing through it all, transparent and clear,
叫び声上げる 舞い戻る 手に触れる
Crying out, returning to dance, touching with my hands.
失敗したって学んでいく...
Even if I fail, I'll keep learning...
...もうこのままずっと降りやまない 雨の世界だ
...In this world of rain that won't stop falling like this.
愛するしかない それしかない 気配じゃないから
I have to love it, that's all there is, it's not just a presence.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
Yeah, it's turned blank. Which page of my youth was it?
忘れ物思い出せないまま 忘れそう
Unable to remember what I've forgotten, I'm about to forget.
ああ... このままじゃ
Ah... if it stays like this...
風の形見えない 見えないよ あなただって
The shape of the wind is invisible, invisible, even to you.
あなただって同じ じっとしていられない 動き
You're the same, unable to stay still, this movement...
出すよ この身かけて
...will start, risking this life.
零さないよう 舞い踊って しょうがないさ
So as not to spill, dancing, it can't be helped.
ねえ このままずっと降りやまない 雨の世界だ
Hey, in this world of rain that won't stop falling like this.
もう寂しくない 人はなれる 生き物だから
I'm not lonely anymore, because humans are creatures that can adapt.
そう白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
Yeah, it's turned blank. Which page of my youth was it?
今君に会いたいと涙 こらえて
I want to see you now, holding back my tears.
さよならだって さよならなんて 認めたくないけど
Even if it's a goodbye, I don't want to accept it, but...
雨上がりのこの世界が 眩しいから
...this world after the rain is just so bright.
もう帰らない 振り返らない 思い出とともに
I won't go back, I won't look back, together with my memories.
新しい風に煽られ
Buffeted by a new wind,
そしてまた 君に会いたいと願い 駆けていく
...and once again, wishing to see you, I run.
駆けていく
I run.
声聴かせてください！
Let me hear your voices!
切らさないで 指深いほどに
Don't let it end, the deeper the fingers go,
隠せない どこにいようが
...the more it can't be hidden, no matter where I am.
輝くものしか ここにない
There's nothing here but things that shine.
日々は一進一退 落ち着かない
Days are a series of ups and downs, restless.
絶えない傷でもギリギリ耐えて
Even with endless wounds, barely enduring...
謳歌しな
...just enjoy it.
いつかきっとじゃない 今に刺激はない
It's not 'someday surely', there's no excitement in the 'now'.
確かなビートが示している上へ
A certain beat is pointing upwards.
行けよ
Go!
咲かせ 咲かせよ 咲かせ切るまで
Bloom, let it bloom, until it blooms fully.
澄み切る闇は 無限の木霊達
The clear darkness is filled with infinite echoes.
旅するのは理屈じゃないの
Traveling is not about logic.
瞬く命よ 咲き誇れ
Twinkling life, bloom in full glory.
殻にこもって 怯えぬ背に吹く
Shutting yourself away, on a back that doesn't fear,
風はない 負けてたまるか
...there is no wind. I won't let myself lose.
開拓者達の 夢の跡
The traces of pioneers' dreams.
自分に期待して何が悪い
What's wrong with expecting things from yourself?
本当の敵も味方も己って
Knowing that the true enemy and ally are yourself,
ほら正解
...see, that's the answer.
だから正気と狂気でギリギリ舞い
So, dance on the edge of sanity and madness.
次から次へと過去に手を振って
Waving goodbye to the past, one after another,
行けよ
Go!
鳴らせ 鳴らせ 胸の...
Let it ring, let it ring, the [sound] in your heart...
…咲き誇れ
...bloom proudly
踏み出す先は未開の時代
The path ahead is an unexplored era
立ち止まってる時間はないの
There's no time to stand still
一陣の風を巻き起こせ
Stir up a sudden gust of wind
壁を作るな 足を止めるな
Don't build walls, don't stop moving
無情な嵐 さす傘はなし
A heartless storm, no umbrella to hold
永遠など望みはしないの
I don't wish for things like eternity
今を満たしたいわ
I want to fill the 'now'
さあ 化せ 化せ よさぁ 化せ 切り抜くまで
Now, transform, transform, come on, transform until the end
澄み切り闇は無限の木立
The clear darkness is a grove of infinity
また砕け散るこの身じゃないの
This body won't just crumble and scatter again
またたく火の地を咲き誇れ
Let the blood of the flickering fire bloom proudly
最高峰へ
To the highest peak
白いカーテンの末 似たような朝のようで
Beyond the white curtains, it seems like just another morning
まるで違う 交差するSighs 新しく目覚めるBedmaster
Entirely different, intersecting sighs, a newly awakened Bedmaster
Tick-tock another story テンポは居合わず 私アドメ
Tick-tock another story, the tempo doesn't match, I adome
I don't care about the story 何を信じる？
I don't care about the story, what do you believe in?
眩しくてそらした初期衝動 今 追随して
Dazzled, I turned away from that initial impulse, now I'm following it
空の愛の歌描いて 聞き飽きてきたでしょ
Drawing empty love songs, you're getting tired of hearing them, right?
流行性の反存在 退屈してんじゃない？
A trendy anti-existence, aren't you bored?
I'm ready to dance!
千載一遇のニュアンスで 有象無象 後続のシンパシーで
With a once-in-a-lifetime nuance, the masses, with subsequent sympathy
直感主義のイノセンスで 有象無象 奇跡も世界も自分次第で
With intuitive innocence, the masses, miracles and the world are all up to you
最上級の革命の狼煙は 覚悟 変化を恐れない覚悟
The signal fire for the ultimate revolution is resolve, the resolve not to fear change
乾いて 大地を駆けろ 唯一の光
Thirsting, run across the earth, the one and only light
変えたい 変えたい 平穏さが魂を焚きつける
I want to change, I want to change, the tranquility stokes my soul
独占 マンネリ 一刀両断 サプライズで ドラマチックなヒストリーにしよう
Monopoly, mannerism, cutting in two, with a surprise, let's make it a dramatic history
アンカー 夜空に架けた 遠すぎる欠片
Anchor, cast into the night sky, fragments too far away
光速超え見せられるまで醒めない
Surpassing the speed of light, I won't wake until I'm shown
惑星が導き出されて What do you need? What do you take? 存在の場所は
The planets are led out, what do you need? What do you take? The place of existence is
不穏な夢なら青天井 無限歩高でハイテンション 突き抜ける銀河の果てで 一呼吸
If it's an unsettling dream, the sky's the limit, high tension at infinite walking height, taking a breath at the edge of the galaxy
モニター越しの輝きじゃ つまんない
Glittering through a monitor is boring
飛び出す 創造なら Go to heaven 目をそらさず見ててね 終焉の黎明
Leaping out, if it's creation, go to heaven, watch without turning away, the dawn of the end
踏み出した刹那の色を作る アップデート 希望も絶望も自分次第で
Creating the color of the moment I stepped out, update, hope and despair are both up to you
最上級の革命の火蓋は 覚悟 変化を恐れず
The start of the ultimate revolution is resolve, without fearing change
ジョジョ Let's go
Chou chou Let's go
乾いた心に満ちた
Filled my dried heart
孤高の光 閉じては
Closed the solitary light
作るの連続が
A series of creations
未来を連れてくる
Brings the future
持て余す一度きりの
In this one-time-only
サプライズで止まったらキスにしよう
Overwhelming surprise, let's kiss if we stop
ア・マ・レ・ス・ジャン
A-Ma-Re-S-Jan
大阪ー！
Osaka!
おおきに！おおきに！おおきに！おおきに！
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石、
So, the diamond in the rough who appeared like a comet,
バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei is here!
すいちゃんはー？
How is Sui-chan?
今日もかわいいー！
Cute today as well!
いいね。
Nice.
これが大阪の空気。
This is the air of Osaka.
これが大阪の空気ー！
This is the air of Osaka!
いやもう始まる前から皆さん「すいちゃん今日も可愛い！」ひっきりなしでしたね。
Even before the show started, you all were saying "Sui-chan is cute today!" non-stop.
聞いてましたよ。裏でずっと。
I was listening. From backstage, the whole time.
ものなったら「お前ら声足りてねーぞ！」みたいな人いましたよね。
There was even someone going, "You guys aren't loud enough!"
いや本当になんかね、もう始まる前からずっと楽しくて。
Really, I've been having so much fun even before we started.
星街すいせいライブツアー2024 "Spectra of Nova" 第二公演です！
It's the second performance of Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 "Spectra of Nova"!
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆様ようこそいらっしゃいました。
Welcome, everyone.
いや、ちょっと交通大丈夫でした？
By the way, was the transportation okay?
私ずっとさ、Twitterでさ、ずっとさ、
I was on Twitter all the time,
「みんな大丈夫かな？大丈夫かな？」ってずっとツイートしてたんですけど。
tweeting things like, "I wonder if everyone is okay?"
今日ここに来られなかったーって人！
Who is someone who couldn't come here today!
あれ？いやいるいる、みんないる。
Huh? No, they're here, everyone's here.
ここに無事たどり着けたよーって人！
Who successfully made it here safely!
イェーイ！
Yay!
よかった。
Good.
あのですね、実はあの、前回ですね、埼玉公演で
Actually, last time at the Saitama performance,
携帯持って、あの、そこでプレミア公開の枠を立てたりしてたんですけど。
I had my phone and set up a premiere screening thread there.
今日はここでエゴサして「たどり着けなかった」って人がいたら
I was going to egosearch here today and if there were people who "couldn't make it",
「うわあああ、たどり着けなかったって、うわあああ」って言う回をしようと思ったんだけど、
I'd do a bit like "Uwaaa, you couldn't make it, uwaaa", but...
あの、携帯を忘れてきました。
...I forgot my phone.
楽屋に。すみません。
In the dressing room. Sorry.
すみません。ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry. My apologies.
だから今日ないの。ごめん本当に。
So I don't have it today. Sorry, really.
え？かわいい？
Eh? Cute?
あんなところもかわいいと？ありがとうございます。いやいやそんなそんな。
Even that part is cute? Thank you. No no, it's nothing.
ということで、大阪の人ってちなみに、
By the way, regarding the people from Osaka,
大阪らへんに住んでますよって人はちなみにどれくらい？
how many of you live around Osaka?
めっちゃいるじゃん！ほぼ大阪じゃん！
There's so many! Almost everyone is from Osaka!
え、大阪じゃないよって人！
Eh, people who aren't from Osaka!
お、ほぼ大阪じゃないじゃん！あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, almost everyone is NOT from Osaka! Ah, I see.
いやいいですね、楽しい。
That's great, this is fun.
はい、ということで台本をめくって…
Okay, so turning the script...
なんと皆さん、先日発表したんですけれども、
Actually everyone, I announced it the other day, but...
ついに武道館ライブ決定しましたー！
a Budokan live is finally confirmed!
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
新しいアルバムもね、出ます。
A new album is coming out too.
あ、実はあの、今日のここの公演で実は
Ah, actually, at today's venue,
予約ができたらしいんですけど、ここで予約したよって人！
it seems you could pre-order, so who pre-ordered here!
お、めっちゃいる！お、ありがとう！
Oh, there's so many! Oh, thank you!
なんかね可愛いやつがついてくるらしいからね、楽しみにしてて下さい。
I heard some cute bonus comes with it, so look forward to it.
そして、バンドさーん！
And, the band members!
ジャカジャンジャカジャン！はい、
Jaka-jan jaka-jan! Yes,
セカンドそして埼玉公演から引き続きの皆様でございます。
they are the same members from the second and Saitama performances.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして配信ももちろんあります！
And of course, there's a livestream too!
ここに来られなかった人もね、いっぱいいますからね。
There are many people who couldn't come here too.
いや、見てくださいすいちゃんのこの可愛い姿を。
Look at Sui-chan's cute appearance.
え、どんなポーズしたらいいんだろう。
Eh, what kind of pose should I do?
キリルン？
Kirirun?
かわいいー！
Cute!
え、指さし！
Eh, finger point!
ピース！
Peace!
ボキャブラリーがないですね。
I'm running out of vocabulary.
あばっちこ！
A-batchi-ko!
ピース！
Peace!
そして韓国でのライブビューイングも行っております。
And we are also holding a live viewing in Korea.
안녕하세요!
Annyeonghaseyo!
いいですねー。
Nice.
はい、そしてライブの感想は、
Yes, and for your thoughts on the concert,
ハッシュタグ「駆け抜けろ星街」でたくさんツイートしてください！
please tweet a lot with the hashtag #KakenukeroHoshimachi!
ほい！
Hoi!
YouTube、TikTokでご覧の方は、ここまで！
For those watching on YouTube and TikTok, this is the end!
この先を無料で見られると思うな！
Don't think you can see the rest for free!
そうだ！そうだ！(笑)
That's right! That's right! (laughs)
ぜひね、概要欄から配信サイトに飛んで、
Please go to the streaming site from the description box,
ぜひチケットを買ってください！
and be sure to buy a ticket!
買ってー！
Buy it!
はい、今回はですね、もう埼玉公演から、
Yes, for this tour, already starting from the Saitama concert,
実はもうセトリが違うんですよ。
the setlist is actually already different.
気づいた？
Did you notice?
実はセトリがもう違うので、もう、
Actually, since the setlist is already different,
ここから先はもっとセトリが違います。
from here on out, it will be even more different.
さあ何を歌うのか。
So, what will I sing next?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
無料パートは終了いたしました。
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free portion of the show has ended.
Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended.
Thank you for watching.